Guide to the Dorothy Porter Wesley Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Dorothy Porter Wesley papers
1847-2011
JWJ MSS 93
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
180
(350 boxes)
The collection consists chiefly of the correspondence, writings, biographical materials, research files, photographs, and personal papers of librarian, curator and bibliophile Dorothy Porter Wesley. The bulk of the collection is comprised of research materials relating to various subjects pertaining to African American history, culture, and bibliography, including the following: African-American abolitionists Sarah Remond and William C. Nell, African American literature, African literature, and Afro-Brazilian literature. The collection also includes records of the Association for the Study of African-American Life and History.
Wesley, Dorothy Porter, 1905-1995
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from William Reese Co., (Swann African American sale, New York, 2012 March 1, lot 296) on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2012.
Custodial History
Materials were received directly from Swann Auction Galleries. The July 2012 addition, was received from the William Reese Co., after shipment from Florida where it had been found in storage by Wesley's family. The November 2012 addition was received from Swann Auction Galleries via the William Reese Co. after members of Wesley's family sent additional materials to Swann Auction Galleries.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
This collection may be housed off-site at Yale's Library Shelving Facility (LSF). To determine if all or part of this collection is housed off-site please check the library's online catalog, Orbis; material for which the location is given as "LSF" must be requested 36 hours in advance. Please consult with Beinecke Access Services for more information.
Dorothy Porter Wesley (1905-1995)
Dorothy Burnett Porter Wesley (1905-1995) librarian, curator and bibliophile, was born on May 25, 1905 in Warrenton, Virginia to physician Hayes Joseph Burnett and tennis player Roberta ("Bertha") Ball Burnett. Wesley, the eldest of four children, grew up in Montclair, New Jersey. She graduated from Miner Normal School, Washington D.C. in 1925 with the intention of becoming a teacher. Wesley worked as a library assistant in the Miner Normal School library where she worked with librarian Lula V. Allan who encouraged her to pursue a career in library science. Wesley enrolled in Howard University in 1926 and received a BA in 1928. After graduation from Howard University in 1928, Wesley began work as a full-time librarian at Howard University. In 1928 Wesley enrolled at Colombia University's School of Library Science where Wesley received a Master's in Library Science in 1931. In 1930, Wesley began work as curator of the Moorland Foundation, now known as the Moorland-Spingarn Research Center, at Howard University and worked to build collections documenting the African diaspora until her retirement in 1973. Under Wesley's administration, the Moorland-Spingarn Research Center became a world-renowned institution for the history and culture of people of African descent. After retirement, Wesley worked as a consultant for Radcliffe University's Black Women Oral History Archive and authored several articles, and books pertaining to librarianship and the African diaspora. Books authored by Dorothy Porter Wesley include Early Negro Writing, 1760-1837 (1971), and Afro-Braziliana: A Working Bibliography (1978). Wesley married artist and art history professor James Amos Porter (1905-1970) and had a daughter, Constance Porter Uzelac (1939-2012). After James Porter's death in 1970, she married former Wilberforce University president and African American historian, Charles Harris Wesley in 1979. Dorothy worked with Charles on a variety of projects including research for a bibliography on abolitionist William Cooper Nell until Charles's death in 1987. William Cooper Nell, Nineteenth-Century African American Abolitionist, Historian, Integrationist: Selected Writings 1832-1874 (2002) was later published by Constance Porter Uzelac in 2001. Dorothy Porter Wesley died in Broward County, Florida in 1995.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists chiefly of the correspondence, writings, biographical materials, research files, photographs, and personal papers of librarian, curator and bibliophile Dorothy Porter Wesley. The bulk of the collection is comprised of research materials relating to various subjects relating to African American history, culture, and bibliography, including the following: African-American abolitionists Sarah Remond and William C. Nell, African American literature, African literature, and Afro-Brazilian literature. The collection also includes records of the Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and History.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series: Series I. Correspondence, 1870-2011. Series II. Professional Papers, 1869-2003. Series III. Research Files, 1847-2004. Series IV. Personal Papers, 1869-2006.
African American abolitionists; African American authors -- Bibliography; African American librarians; African literature -- Bibliography; Brazilian literature -- Bibliography; Bibliographers -- United States; Nell, William C. (William Cooper), 1816-1874; Remond, Sarah Parker, 1826-1894; Wesley, Dorothy Porter, 1905-1995; Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and History
- Series I. Correspondence, 1870-2011
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence consists of letters to and from or indirectly received by Dorothy Porter Wesley and her family. The series documents Wesley's professional and personal activities as librarian and curator at the Moorland-Spingarn Research Center as well as her commitments as a consultant on the Black Women's Oral History Project at Radcliffe Institue, and in organizations such as The Association for the Study of African American Life and History, the National Council of Negro Women, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc., and the W.E.B. Dubois Research Institute at Harvard University.
  General Correspondence documents Wesley's professional activities, including her work with former Howard University president Mordecai Wyatt Johnson, sociologist Adelaide McGuinn Cromwell, John Wesley Blassingame, and authors Charles L. Blockson and Dorothy Sterling. Family Correspondence includes letters to and from Dorothy Porter Wesley as well as third-party subjects. Dorothy Porter Wesley's daughter Constance Porter Uzelac, and husbands James Amos Porter and Charles Harris Wesley are included in this series. Third Party Correspondence includes correspondence collected by Dorothy Porter Wesley during her lifetime.
  Arrangement
  This series is organized into three sub-series: General Correspondence; Family Correspondence; and Third Party Correspondence. Materials in each subseries are arranged alphabetically by last name and chronologically within folders.
  - General Correspondence, Circa 1930-1996
    - "A" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
    - "A" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
    - Abajian, James Hill, 1969-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
    - Achille, Louis, 1933-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14-17)
    - African American Museums Association, 1982-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Afro-American Historical and Cultural Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Afro-American Historical and Genealogical Society, 1977-1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Alakja, Ayo, 1962- (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Alden, John, 1966-1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Alexander, Adele Logan, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Alexander, Eleanor, 1988- (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Alexander, Margaret Abigail Walker, 1971-1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Allan, Bertha, Circa 1963 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Allan, Lula, 1927-1968 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Allen, Samuel, 1970-1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Allen, William Duncan, 1939-1989 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, 1980-1995 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Alpha Wives of Washington D.C., 1962-1995 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - American Antiquarian Society, 1934-1995 (Box 4, Folder 32-37)
    - AARP (American Association of Retired Persons), 1976-1983 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - American Library Association, 1934-1992 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - American Visions, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Amistad Research Center, 1979-1995 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Amos, Geraldine Odester, 1963-1986 (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
    - Andrews, Richard, 1939-1971 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Anonye, Chinedozi, A., 1936-1989 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Apejoye, Titus B., 1966- (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Arno Press, 1968-1980 (Box 6, Folder 47-49)
    - Arno Press, 1968- (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 962)
    - Artis, Lydia, 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Asher, Lila, 1962-1991 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Associated Publishers, 1982-1993 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Associates of the Boston Public Library, 1989-1995 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Association of Howard University Retirees, 1983-1992 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Association for the Study of African-American Life and History, 1934-1995 (Box 7, Folder 55-56)
    - Atheneum Publishers, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Atlanta University, 1938-1977 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Atlantic Research Corporation, 1961-1967 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Austin, Elise, 1953-1978 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Avant, Frank W., 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Azikiwe, Nnamdi, 1904-1996, 1950-1964 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - "B" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 8, Folder 63-69)
    - "B" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 9, Folder 70-75)
    - "B" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 10, Folder 76-79)
    - Baa, Enid M., 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Balch Institute for Ethnic Studies, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Ballard, Currie, 1991- (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Baltimore, Thelma, 1980-1993 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - Barber, Connie, 1951-1995 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Barker, Elizabeth, 1963-1980 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Barrows, Isabel C., 1966- (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Battle, Thomas C., 1972-1992 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Beacon Press, 1968-1995 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Berkley, Constance, 1975-1979 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - Berry, Faith, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Bethune Museum-Archives, 1985-1993 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - Bhan, Esme, 1947-, 1983-1995 (Box 12, Folder 92-94)
      - Oversize, 1959- (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 963)
    - Bibliographical Society of America, 1944-1982 (Box 12, Folder 95)
    - Billingsley, Andy, 1973-1988 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    - Bishop, David, circa 1993 (Box 12, Folder 97)
    - Black Abolitionist Papers Project, 1979-1991 (Box 12, Folder 98)
    - Blackburn, Helen, 1978-1987 (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - Black Women in Sisterhood for Action (BISA), 1990-1995 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - Bland, Philip, 1968-1974 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - Blassingame, John W., 1940-2000, 1969-1985 (Box 13, Folder 102)
      - Oversize, 1975- (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 964)
    - Blevins, Anna Lou, 1977- (Box 13, Folder 103)
    - Blockson, Charles L., 1973-1994 (Box 13, Folder 104-105)
    - Boston (Mass.). Public Library, 1967-1984 (Box 13, Folder 106)
      - Oversize, 1975- (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 965)
    - Boston University, 1962-1982 (Box 13, Folder 107)
    - Boulton, Rudyerd, 1901-1983, 1950-1964 (Box 13, Folder 108)
    - Boulware, Marcus H., 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 109)
    - Bourgeous, Jean-Lois, 1982- (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - Britton, Helen, 1988-1995 (Box 13, Folder 111)
    - Brooks, Charlotte, 1989-1992 (Box 13, Folder 112)
    - Brooks, Evelyn, 1981-1986 (Box 14, Folder 113)
    - Brooks, Mildred, 1972-1992 (Box 14, Folder 114)
    - Brown, Bennie, 1964-1984 (Box 14, Folder 115)
    - Brown, Dillard, 1950-1970 (Box 14, Folder 116)
    - Brown, Sterling, 1949-1972 (Box 14, Folder 117)
    - Buckler, Helen, 1945-1954 (Box 14, Folder 118)
    - Burkett, Randall K., 1984-1992 (Box 15, Folder 119)
    - Butcher, James, 1958-1991 (Box 15, Folder 120)
    - Buttler, Lillian, 1975-1993 (Box 15, Folder 121)
    - Butterfield, Roger, 1968-1978 (Box 15, Folder 122)
    - "C" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 16, Folder 123-128)
    - "C" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 17, Folder 129-130)
    - Calhoun, Cecelia, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 131)
    - Campbell, Hazel, 1982-1986 (Box 17, Folder 132)
    - Cannon, Raymond, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 133)
    - Carlson Publishing, 1991-1993 (Box 17, Folder 134)
    - Carter, Hazel, 1951-1992 (Box 17, Folder 135)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1924-, 1980-1988 (Box 17, Folder 136)
    - Caspa, Kungaba, 1973-1979 (Box 17, Folder 137)
    - Center for Research Libraries, 1972-1976 (Box 17, Folder 138)
    - Central State University, 1987-1995 (Box 17, Folder 139)
    - Charles L. Blockson Center, 1994- (Box 17, Folder 140)
    - Charles H. Thompson Lecture-Colloquium Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 17, Folder 141)
    - Cheek, James, 1970-1990 (Box 18, Folder 142)
    - Cheyney State College, 1976- (Box 18, Folder 143)
    - Chicago Public Library, 1973-1990 (Box 18, Folder 144)
    - Chindango, Crispin, 1986-1992 (Box 18, Folder 145)
    - Clark, Edward, 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 146)
    - Clayborn, Isadore Huddleston, 1981-1987 (Box 18, Folder 147)
    - Cobb, Hilda, 1949-1976 (Box 18, Folder 148)
    - Cocroft, Horace, 1968-1993 (Box 18, Folder 149)
    - Collier, Charlotte, 1970-1980 (Box 18, Folder 150)
    - Columbia Historical Society, 1974-1989 (Box 18, Folder 151)
    - Columbia Travel Service, 1962- (Box 18, Folder 152)
    - Columbia University, 1930-1994 (Box 18, Folder 153)
    - Columbia University. Press, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 154)
    - Combs, Marion, 1972-1984 (Box 18, Folder 155)
    - Commonwealth of Massachusetts, 1967-1980 (Box 19, Folder 156)
    - Conrad, Emmett, 1981-1986 (Box 19, Folder 157)
    - Conrad Incorporated, 1973- (Box 19, Folder 158)
    - Contemporary Authors, 1981-1986 (Box 19, Folder 159)
    - Cook, William Marion, 1939- (Box 19, Folder 160)
    - Cooke, Paul Phillips, 1973-1994 (Box 19, Folder 161)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1970-1987 (Box 19, Folder 162)
    - Cornell University, 1937-1992 (Box 19, Folder 163)
    - Cotman, Ivan, 1984-1986 (Box 19, Folder 164)
    - Craft, Thomas, 1980-1991 (Box 19, Folder 165)
    - Crampton, Louis, 1961-1967 (Box 19, Folder 166)
    - Crawford, Bryant, 1981-1987 (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Crawford, Evans, 1981-1990 (Box 19, Folder 168)
    - Cromwell, Adelaide M., 1968-1992 (Box 19, Folder 169)
    - Crossey, John M. D., 1965-1973 (Box 19, Folder 170)
    - Crowell, Clara, 1982-1985 (Box 19, Folder 171)
    - Cunningham, Joel, 1990-1994 (Box 19, Folder 172)
    - Cunningham, William, 1973- (Box 19, Folder 173)
    - Cureau, Harold, 1975- (Box 19, Folder 174)
    - "D" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 20, Folder 175-180)
    - "D" general, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 21, Folder 181-182)
    - Dabney, Hazel, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 183)
    - Daniel, A. Mercer (Allen Mercer), 1887-1976, 1972-1975 (Box 21, Folder 184)
    - Daniel, Walter C., 1936-1988 (Box 21, Folder 185)
    - Davis, Ethel, 1977-1989 (Box 21, Folder 186)
    - Davis, Lenwood G., 1976-1980 (Box 21, Folder 187)
    - Davis, Thaddius, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 188)
    - Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, 1974-1983 (Box 21, Folder 189)
    - Delhante, Ernesto, 1947-1959 (Box 21, Folder 190)
    - Dictionary of American Negro Biography, 1974-1995 (Box 21, Folder 191)
    - Dickerson, Dennis, 1982-1992 (Box 21, Folder 192)
    - Dillard University, 1970-1986 (Box 22, Folder 193)
    - District of Columbia Art Association, 1980-1985 (Box 22, Folder 194-195)
    - District of Columbia Public Library, 1981-1994 (Box 22, Folder 196)
    - Dodson, Owen, 1972-1983 (Box 22, Folder 197)
    - Dozier, Lois G., 1972-1985 (Box 22, Folder 198)
    - Driscoll, Emily, 1951- (Box 22, Folder 199)
    - Driskell, David, 1971-1993 (Box 22, Folder 200)
    - Duncan, Gladys, 1945-1982 (Box 22, Folder 201)
    - Durley, Gerald, 1979-1984 (Box 22, Folder 202)
    - "E" General, Circa 1930-1995 (Box 23, Folder 203-204)
    - Ellington, Duke, 1899-1974., 1939- (Box 23, Folder 205)
    - Ellis, Ethel, 1973-1994 (Box 23, Folder 206-207)
    - Ellis, Olga, 1978-1984 (Box 23, Folder 208)
    - Essex Institute, 1967-1992 (Box 23, Folder 209)
    - Everett, Annie G., 1973-1992 (Box 23, Folder 210-211)
    - "F" General, Circa 1930-1995 (Box 24, Folder 212-218)
    - Falaiye, Michael, 1973-1979 (Box 25, Folder 219)
    - Federal Life and Casulty Company, 1956- (Box 25, Folder 220)
    - Fellows, Dorkas, 1873-1938, 1934-1935 (Box 25, Folder 221)
    - Feng, Yen-Tsai, 1969-1994 (Box 25, Folder 222)
    - Fields, Oscar, 1978-1994 (Box 25, Folder 223)
    - Fisher, Walter, 1986-1988 (Box 25, Folder 224)
    - Fisk University. Library, 1938-1992 (Box 25, Folder 225)
    - Fitzhugh, Howard N. (Howard Naylor), 1909-1992, 1970-1988 (Box 25, Folder 226)
    - Fleming, John, 1984-1994 (Box 25, Folder 227)
    - Flippin, Katherine Stewart, 1906-, 1971-1988 (Box 25, Folder 228)
    - Florence, Virginia, 1973-1975 (Box 25, Folder 229)
    - Ford Foundation, 1962-1983 (Box 26, Folder 230-231)
    - Franklin, John Hope, 1915-2009, 1954-1994 (Box 26, Folder 232-233)
    - Frazier, E. Franklin, 1894-1962., 1945-1961 (Box 26, Folder 234)
    - Friends of the Kennedy Center, 1986-1987 (Box 26, Folder 235)
    - Friends of the Leopold Senghor Foundation, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 236)
    - Friends of the Museum of Africa, 1975-1990 (Box 26, Folder 237)
    - Fuji, Susumu, 1960- (Box 26, Folder 238)
    - "G" General, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 27, Folder 239-247)
    - Gadsen, Marie, 1985-1994 (Box 28, Folder 248)
    - Garvin, Charles H., 1941-1974 (Box 28, Folder 249)
    - Gates, Henry Louis, Jr., 1987-1995 (Box 28, Folder 250)
    - Gauld, Charles, 1951-1962 (Box 28, Folder 251)
    - GK Hall & Company, 1971-1995 (Box 28, Folder 252-256)
    - GK Hall & Company, 1971-1995 (Box 29, Folder 257-258)
    - Glover, Denise, 1981-1990 (Box 29, Folder 259)
    - Goins, John, 1981-1995 (Box 29, Folder 260)
    - Gordon, William, 1973-1977 (Box 29, Folder 261)
    - Gourdin, Amalia, 1968-1990 (Box 29, Folder 262)
      - Oversize, 1987-1989 (Box 118 (Oversize), Folder 966)
    - Graves, Patsy, 1962-1994 (Box 29, Folder 263)
    - Graves, Patsy, 1962-1994 (Box 30, Folder 264-265)
    - Gray, Estrelda, 1982-1992 (Box 30, Folder 266)
    - Green, Inez, 1990-1994 (Box 30, Folder 267)
    - Greenberg, Marion, 1968- (Box 30, Folder 268)
    - Greene, Lorenzo, 1978-1988 (Box 30, Folder 269-270)
    - Greenlee, Marcia Mcadoo, 1972-1985 (Box 30, Folder 271)
    - Groomes, Thelma, 1988-1994 (Box 30, Folder 272)
    - Gross, Bella, 1931-1955 (Box 30, Folder 273-274)
    - "H" General, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 31, Folder 275-279)
    - "H" General, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 32, Folder 280-284)
    - "H" General, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 33, Folder 285-287)
    - Haines, Carrie, 1974-1978 (Box 33, Folder 288)
    - Haith, Dorothy May, 1979-1989 (Box 33, Folder 289)
    - Haley, George, 1984-1991 (Box 33, Folder 290)
    - Hamilton, West, 1973-1979 (Box 33, Folder 291)
    - Hanawalt, Jean, 1972-1975 (Box 33, Folder 292)
    - Handy, D. Antoinette, 1930-2002, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 293)
    - Hansberry, Myrtle, 1976- (Box 33, Folder 294)
    - Hansberry, William Leo, 1972- (Box 33, Folder 295)
    - Harden, Julia, 1951-1988 (Box 33, Folder 296)
    - Harding, Janice, 1988- (Box 33, Folder 297)
    - Harley, Sheron, 1975-1995 (Box 34, Folder 298)
    - Harris, Joseph, 1977-1993 (Box 34, Folder 299)
    - Harris, Janette Hoston, 1939-, 1982-1986 (Box 34, Folder 300)
    - Harvard College Library, 1937- (Box 34, Folder 301)
    - Harvard University W.E.B. Dubois Institute, 1981-1995 (Box 34, Folder 302-303)
    - Hatch-Billops Collection, Inc., 1980-1995 (Box 34, Folder 304)
    - Hayes, Angella, 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 305)
    - Hayes, Ola, 1987-1992 (Box 34, Folder 306)
    - Heartman, Charles F. (Charles Frederick), 1883-1953., 1931-1967 (Box 34, Folder 307)
    - Henderson, Harry, 1972-1995 (Box 35, Folder 308)
    - Herbert, Lehman, 1977-1978 (Box 35, Folder 309)
    - Higginbotham, A. Leon, Jr., 1928-1998, 1982-1994 (Box 35, Folder 310)
    - Hill, Louise, 1962- (Box 35, Folder 311)
    - Hiram Lodge, 1982-1986 (Box 35, Folder 312)
    - Historical Society of Washington, D.C., 1991-1994 (Box 35, Folder 313)
    - Holloman, Charlotte Wesley, 1961- (Box 35, Folder 314)
    - Hope, Marion, 1952-1956 (Box 35, Folder 315)
    - Howard, Harriet, 1957-1973 (Box 35, Folder 316)
    - Howard University Andrew Rankin Memorial, 1982-1993 (Box 35, Folder 317)
    - Howard University Carnegie Library, 1931-1936 (Box 35, Folder 318)
    - Howard University. College of Fine Arts, 1986-1995 (Box 35, Folder 319)
    - Howard University. Department of History, 1972-1992 (Box 35, Folder 320)
    - Howard University. faculty Wives Club, 1957-1991 (Box 36, Folder 321)
    - Howard University Library, 1936-1993 (Box 36, Folder 322)
    - Howard University Phi Beta Kappa, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 323)
    - Howard University Press, 1940-1993 (Box 36, Folder 324)
    - Howard University. School of Law, 1981-1989 (Box 36, Folder 325)
    - Howard University. School of Religion, 1977- (Box 36, Folder 326)
    - Howard University Thompson Lecture Colloquium Committee, 1980-1995 (Box 36, Folder 327)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967., 1949-1966 (Box 36, Folder 328)
    - Hunton, Dorothy, 1972-1990 (Box 36, Folder 329)
    - Hurley, Catherine, 1960-1977 (Box 36, Folder 330)
    - Hutson, Alphaeus, 1960-1962 (Box 36, Folder 331)
    - Hutson, Jean Blackwell, 1914-1998, 1968-1989 (Box 36, Folder 332)
    - "I" General, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 37, Folder 333-334)
    - Igun, Adenola A., 1958-1987 (Box 37, Folder 335)
    - Ingram, Goins, 1985-1994 (Box 37, Folder 336)
    - Institute of Jamaica, 1973-1974 (Box 37, Folder 337)
    - Isaacs, Esther, 1977-1979 (Box 37, Folder 338)
    - "J" General, Circa 1930-1995 (Box 38, Folder 339-344)
    - Jack and Jill of America, Inc., 1984-1991 (Box 39, Folder 345)
    - Jackson, Alice, 1972-1983 (Box 39, Folder 346-347)
    - Jackson State University, 1968-1994 (Box 39, Folder 348-349)
    - Jacobs, Donald, 1968-1993 (Box 39, Folder 350-351)
    - James, Edward, 1959-1971 (Box 39, Folder 352)
    - Jenkins, Betty, 1968-1995 (Box 39, Folder 353-354)
    - Jenkins, Timothy, 1982-1988 (Box 40, Folder 355)
    - Johnson, Catherine, 1950-1990 (Box 40, Folder 356)
    - Johnson, James, 1981-1992 (Box 40, Folder 357)
    - Johnson, Mordecai W. (Mordecai Wyatt), 1890-1976, 1931-1960 (Box 40, Folder 358)
    - Johnson, Eileen, 1994- (Box 40, Folder 359)
    - Jones, Steven, 1973-1995 (Box 40, Folder 360-362)
    - Josey, Elonnie Junius, 1924-2009, 1967-1989 (Box 41, Folder 363)
    - Journal of Negro History, 1966-1994 (Box 41, Folder 364)
    - Joyce, Donald, 1948-1978 (Box 41, Folder 365)
    - Julius Rosenwald Fund, 1930-1931 (Box 41, Folder 366)
    - "K" General, Circa 1930-1995 (Box 41, Folder 367-372)
    - Keith, Aldridge, 1981-1986 (Box 42, Folder 373)
    - Kennedy, James H., 1973-1976 (Box 42, Folder 374)
    - Kent State University, 1973-1995 (Box 42, Folder 375)
    - Keys, Sylvia, 1972-1992 (Box 42, Folder 376-378)
    - Kinney, William A., 1956- (Box 42, Folder 379)
    - Knopf, Naomi, 1974- (Box 42, Folder 380)
    - Kronstadt, Lilian, 1980-1995 (Box 42, Folder 381)
    - "L" General, Circa 1930-1996 (Box 43, Folder 382-387)
    - Lambert, Carrie, 1959-1963 (Box 43, Folder 388)
    - Langhorne, Joseph Leon, 1975-1988 (Box 43, Folder 389)
    - Leffall, Delores, 1963-1995 (Box 44, Folder 390)
    - Lenox Hill Publishing & Distributing Corp. (Burt Franklin), 1970- (Box 44, Folder 391)
    - Leonard, Walter, 1979-1981 (Box 44, Folder 392)
    - Lewis, James, 1972-1977 (Box 44, Folder 393)
    - Library Company of Philadelphia, 1945-1991 (Box 44, Folder 394)